=Episode 19=
Mother,
I'm taking you back with me.
My child,
we don't have much time.
I only have time
to tell you a few things.
Listen to me.
Your father
may have fallen into demonic corruption
and lost all reason and humanity.
My sudden death back then
was his doing.
Are you saying...
Father murdered you, Mother?
Perhaps
he stopped being your father long ago,
and stopped being my Yunling too.
My child,
I hid a magical artifact
in the Archive Pavilion.
It is called the Demon-Revealing Mirror.
Find it.
If he's no longer your father,
you must kill him.
Do you know what you're saying?
Yunlie,
if Yunling has truly fallen
to demonic corruption,
he's a threat to you and all of Huyun.
If the Demon Lord
seizes this chance to break free,
all of Huyun will become his puppet.
Is that what you want to see?
In the Netherworld,
throughout these endless years,
I've heard Yunling's agonized screams
countless times.
He's in so much pain.
Yunlie...
Help him find release.
Mother.
My child,
to be able
to see you one more time
makes me truly happy.
I'm so happy.
In the days to come,
remember to eat well,
and don't kick off your blankets
like you did when you were little.
Okay?
In this lifetime,
having all of your father's love
and a son as wonderful as you,
I'm already so happy.
It's only a shame that I can't
stay by your side any longer.
Mother?
Mother!
Mother...
Jin Yunlie,
wake up.
Jin Yunlie.
♪I shut out the world, you're all I see♪
♪One glance to last forever,
just you and me♪
Wake up.
Jin Yunlie,
wake up.
♪Lost in the gaps where rain
slips through, life's a fleeting line♪
Jin Yunlie,
wake up.
Jin Yunlie.
♪The wind hasn't risen tonight.
Missing you might be an illness♪
♪The long misty rain scatters in haste♪
♪Letting go may be love's last line♪
Has he already begun
crossing the River of Oblivion?
Then how do I get there?
Xi Yuan,
you want to go to the River of Oblivion?
The River of Oblivion is under
the Netherworld's jurisdiction.
Almost no one has ever
managed to get a soul back from him.
Even so,
I have to try.
Tell me,
how do I get to the River of Oblivion?
When a person is on the verge of death,
their soul has a chance
of reaching the Netherworld.
Alright.
I'm going to find him.
♪After the world fades away,
you alone stay in my sight♪
♪Rouge sachets and jade towers
can't match your dance in the light♪
♪Once the heart knows love's design,
it's you I seek, and intertwine♪
Xi Yuan!
Xi Yuan...
I have to go back.
You can't go against the current.
Turn back!
Out of my way!
All hail the Netherworld Sovereign.
You're already dead, body and soul gone.
Why refuse to
cross the River of Oblivion
and seek your next life?
I can't go.
There is someone I must protect.
Protect?
You have already died,
body and soul gone.
With what will you protect her?
If I refuse to cross,
I still have a chance to return.
Return?
No one has ever
left my domain.
My life and death
are not yours to decide.
The Jin clansman of the Xuanji Realm,
if you persist in this folly,
you shall be cast
into the Unending Hell,
never to reincarnate for all eternity.
Like I said...
There's someone
waiting for me
to return.
Utterly obstinate.
Jin Yunlie,
you shall pay the price for defying
the laws of the Netherworld.
Xi Yuan?
She'd go this far
for you?
What happened to Xi Yuan?
She's risking her life to save you.
So I'll give you one more chance.
The only thing equal in value to a life
is a future.
Every human future
is born of cause and bears its effect.
The law of karma is inexorable.
If you wish to live,
I can only take away her future.
You may leave,
but from this day forward,
I will decide
her future.
Netherworld Sovereign,
it seems you underestimate me
far too much.
How could I hand over
the future of the woman I love
just to save my own skin?
What's more,
it's her future.
I have no right to decide,
and I'd never presume
to decide it for her.
If you demand a price,
then take my future.
I'm the one who went upstream
against the River of Oblivion.
I'm the one who violated
the laws of the Netherworld.
The one who should bear all of this
is me, and me alone.
Not her.
Your future?
You're already dead.
What future do you even have left?
(His future includes me.)
The Gate of Rebirth?
So, you found your way here after all.
Xi Yuan...
How did you...
Jin Yunlie!
You two are separated by life and death.
Naturally, you can't touch one another.
Xi Yuan,
you've trespassed into the Netherworld.
Do you not fear divine punishment?
Shisi?
Is that you?
I never imagined
you'd be the ruler of the Netherworld.
Xi Yuan,
I'm sorry
that you had to see
my true form under these circumstances.
So...
you're the one at the end of
that life-or-death tribulation
you told me about.
♪A love letter, a passionate pursuit,
the envy of everyone♪
♪Bouquets and heartfelt confessions,
leaving me moved and fulfilled♪
♪No matter how long or hard our road,
I don't care♪
♪But you left me with this pain,
forever beyond redemption♪